mobil.com 2018-10-21

# Privacy policy and statement | ExxonMobil

**Effective Date of Privacy Statement: December 21, 2001**

****Most recent update: **May 21, 2018**.

Exxon Mobil Corporation and its affiliated companies, ("ExxonMobil") appreciate your interest in this Web site and other related or linked ExxonMobil sites (Site). Your privacy is important and we want you to understand our practices with respect to gathering information from visitors to the Site and with respect to the uses we make of that information. Please check each portion or page of the Site that you visit. Certain portions or pages of the Site may contain changes to the Privacy Statement applicable to your use of that portion or page, for example, certain applications may request additional information from you.  

**Information and Uses**

When someone visits the Site, our web servers automatically gather information that allows the site to communicate with the visitor's computer during the visit. We also track such information as the number of visits to the site, which parts of the site visitors select, analytics to measure and observe user behavior, IP address (the Internet address assigned to your device from your Internet Service Provider), device type, domain type, browser type (e.g., Firefox, Chrome or Internet Explorer), date and time of day, device screen size. We use such information for purposes including helping us design and administer the Site.

Privacy concerns focus on Personal Information, that is, information that could identify a specific individual such as names, addresses, e-mail addresses, and telephone numbers. If during your visit you personalize the Site, complete an order form, enter a contest, provide survey feedback or submit other information to us, you may provide us with Personal Information. We may collect and use that Personal Information to process your survey feedback for the purpose of improving your experience at our branded sites, to provide you with products or services, to bill you for products and services you request, or to tell you about ExxonMobil products and services which we think may be of interest to you—including via email and text message, to communicate with you for other purposes. We may also use that Personal Information as necessary to protect our rights and the rights of others, including by enforcing our Terms & Conditions, and for any other purpose disclosed to you at the time we collect your information or pursuant to your consent.

As a visitor to our Site, you may be asked to allow us to access geolocation information about your computer or mobile device.  This geolocation information will be used for purposes including to provide the services you request such as showing the location of nearby service stations, and the route to service stations. We may also use this geolocation information to tell you about ExxonMobil products and services, for instance in combination with weather information about the geolocation of your computer or mobile device. If you do not wish for us to use the geolocation information for such purposes, you can decline our request to access the geolocation information.  In that case, some of the services of our Site may not be delivered. We may provide the geolocation information to third parties that assist us in the provision of the services and communications to you through the Site.

As explained below in the section on Dissemination of Information to Third Parties, we do not distribute or sell Personal Information to third parties for the purpose of allowing them to market their products and services to you; moreover, as explained in the Opt Out/Modify Information section, we will make a reasonable effort to remove your Personal Information from our database in such a way that you will not receive future communications from us, if that is your wish. If you notify us that Personal Information previously submitted to our site is no longer accurate, we will make a reasonable effort to make appropriate corrections. To facilitate our efforts to meet your request, it would be helpful if you could let us know the context in which you provided Personal Information, e.g. in connection with promotion of a specific product or service.

**Information Placed on Your Computer**

We may store some information (commonly known as a "cookie") on your computer when you look at or use the Site. This information facilitates customizing your use of the Site and helps to avoid the need for you to re-enter your details every time you visit it. You can erase or block this information from your computer if you want to. (The ‘help’ screen in your browser or computer user manual should tell you how to do this.)

**Targeted Advertising**

We also use the information we collect and receive to provide ads for our Services and to send you promotional communications.  For example, we and our third-party partners may use your information to show you ads on and off our Site, including on third-party social media services.  In doing so, we and our partners may use cookies and other technologies including web beacons and pixels.  For example, when you access an ad, a "cookie" file will be stored on your computer. This information is used to help manage our on-line advertising. To learn more about the third-party ad-serving technology, cookies, and how to "opt-out" please [click here](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/ "this link opens a new browser window") (note: you will be taken to a third-party website).  For additional information on cookies and related technologies, please click here. 

**Information From Children**

This is a general audience web site that is not directed to children younger than 13.  We do not knowingly collect, use or disseminate any personal information from children under the age of 13, unless permitted by law.

**Hyperlinks**

This site has links to sites that ExxonMobil does not own, control or maintain. We cannot be responsible for their privacy policies and practices and we make no representations or warranties about the privacy practices of those sites. Similarly, we cannot be responsible for the policies and practices of any site from which you linked to our Web site. We recommend that you check the privacy policy of other sites and contact the operator if you have concerns or questions.

**Sharing Information with Third Parties**

Communicating via the Internet and sending information, products, and services to you by other means necessarily involves your Personal Information passing through or being handled by third-parties, but ExxonMobil does not sell or distribute your Personal Information to third parties for purposes of allowing them to market their products and services to you.

We employ other companies and individuals to perform functions on our behalf as service providers. Examples include fulfilling orders, deliveries, sending postal mail and e-mail, removing repetitive information from customer lists, analyzing data, providing marketing assistance, processing credit card payments and providing customer service. They have access to Personal Information needed to perform their functions, but may not use it for other purposes.

Personal data collected by ExxonMobil may be transferred among its various divisions and affiliated companies, around the world, as well as transferred to select partners.

We may share your information with other parties when required by law or as necessary to protect our service.  We may also share your information in connection with a transfer of assets, or if we are otherwise involved in a merger or transfer.

We may also share information with third parties in aggregated or non-personally identifiable form.

In addition to the sharing described in this Privacy Statement, we may also share information about you with other third parties when you consent to such sharing.

**Your Choices**

You have a number of choices about how we handle information we collect or receive about you.

_Email_.  You may opt out of receiving future promotional email communications from us by clicking the “Unsubscribe” link in the footer of promotional email communications and updating your preferences.  Please note that we may continue to send you transactional or service-related emails regarding your account.

_SMS and MMS_.  You may opt out of receiving promotional SMS and MMS messages ( i.e., text messages) from us by replying “STOP” to any message, which is free of charge.  Please note that we may respond to your opt-out request with a message confirming that you have successfully opted out.

**Data Transfers**

We may transfer the Personal Information we collect about you to countries other than the country in which the information was originally collected. Those countries may not have the same data protection laws as the country in which you initially provided the information. When we transfer your information to other countries, we will protect that information as described in this Privacy Statement.

Such transfers may involve the transfer of Personal Information from countries within the European Economic Area to countries outside the E.E.A. By submitting data on the Site, the visitor provides explicit consent to these transfers, including transborder transmission of data covered by this Privacy Statement.

**Sensitive Information**

ExxonMobil does not seek any sensitive information from visitors to our Site, unless legally required to do so, for example, in connection with recruiting or hiring. Sensitive information includes a number of types of data relating to: race or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or other similar beliefs, trade union membership, physical or mental health, sexual life or criminal record, or genetic or biometric data. We suggest that you do not provide sensitive information of this nature. However, if you do provide such information, ExxonMobil accepts your explicit consent to use that data in the ways described in this Privacy Statement or in the ways described at the point where such information is disclosed.

**Opt Out/Modify Information**

You can request the removal or modification of your Personal Information by sending an e-mail to the [Data Privacy Office](mailto:data.privacy.office@exxonmobil.com?subject=Opt-out).  We will then make a reasonable effort to accommodate your request. As previously noted, it would be helpful to let us know the context in which you provided Personal Information.

**Conditions of Use, Notices and Revisions**

If you choose to visit our Site, your visit and any dispute over privacy is subject to this Privacy Statement and our General Terms of Use of our Site, including any limitations on damages, arbitration of disputes and application of law provisions. We reserve the right to change this statement at any time without notice.

**Contacting ExxonMobil about the content of this Privacy Statement**

If you have any questions about the content of this Privacy Statement, please contact ExxonMobil's Data Privacy Office at the following address: 

Data Privacy Office   
c/o ExxonMobil Business Support Center Hungary Ltd.  
Váci út 81-85  
Budapest  
H-1139  
Hungary  

When we make material changes to this Privacy Statement, we will post the changes on this page and update the revision date at the top of the Privacy Statement. We encourage you to view our Privacy Statement regularly for updates.

**Cookies, Web Beacons, and Other Technologies**

Our Services may use online technologies called “cookies” and “web beacons,” as well as other local storage technologies.  This section explains what these technologies are and how they may be used.

_Cookies and Other Local Storage Technologies_

Generally speaking, “cookies” are text files that are placed in your device’s browser, and that can be used to help recognize your browser across different web pages, websites, and browsing sessions.  Your browser or device may offer settings related to cookies.  For example, you may be able to configure your browser not to accept cookies or to notify you when a cookie is being sent.  For more information about whether these settings are available, what they do, and how they work, visit your browser or device’s help material.  If you decide not to accept cookies from us, you may not be able to take advantage of all of the features of the Services.

Cookies are stored on your device or in “local storage.” We also use other types of local storage technologies, such as Local Shared Objects (sometimes called “Flash cookies”), in connection with our Services.  These technologies are similar to cookies in that they are stored on your device and can be used to maintain information about your activities and preferences.

However, these other local storage technologies may use parts of your device other than your browser, which means you may not be able to control their use using the browser tools and settings you use to control browser cookies.  For more information about managing Flash cookies, please visit the Adobe Flash Player website.  Your browser’s privacy controls may enable you to manage other types of local storage.

Our Services may use cookies or other local storage technologies in combination with other information about you to enhance and personalize your experience on our Services (or elsewhere online), including:

  * to help authenticate you when you use our Services;
  * to remember your preferences and registration information; to enable a shopping cart;
  * to present and help measure and research the effectiveness of our Service, advertisements, and email communications (by determining which emails you open and act upon); and
  * to customize the content and advertisements provided to you through our Services and on other websites and services you visit.

_Web Beacons_

Web beacons are small pieces of code placed on Web pages, videos, and in emails that can communicate information about your browser and device to a server.  Beacons can be used, among other things, to count the users who visit a Web page or read an email, or to deliver a cookie to the browser of a user viewing a Web page or email.
